Agustín Tomás Escobar Blanc

M.Sc. in Theoretical Physics Pontifical Catholic University Of Chile Mobile: +56971412967

E-Mail: agustin.escobar.blanc@gmail.com

Web: www.agustinescobar.com

GitHub: https://github.com/atescobar

Profile

Ms. Sci. In Physics with experience in numerical computation in python. Experience with TensorFlow's python library in machine learning applied to industry and building data pipelines with Google Cloud Platform. Academic interests lie in condensed matter physics, quantum computation and physics of complex systems. Professional interest in the application of Big Data tools to various industries.

Working Experience

Consultant at Konstruyendo.com (Santiago, Chile, January 1st 2020 to date) Lead Data Scientist in a homologation project to automate the onboarding process for Konstruyendo.com's clients.

Data Scientist at SECOM (Santiago, Chile, July 1st 2019 to date)

Data Scientist at the Communications Secretariat at the Ministry General Secretariat of Government (Chilean Government).

Data Scientist At Management Solution (Santiago, Chile, February 1st 2019 until April 25th)

Assistant 1 at Management Solutions international firm. Currently working in data science in a financial institution.

Challenge 53 - SONDA from the Sin Límites Program (Santiago, Chile, 2018) Used Big Data tools to improve the accuracy of the annual sales of the company

Teacher of Physics and Robotics at Pucalán Montessori High School (Santiago, Chile, February 2018 to February 2019)

Taught physics, robotics and electronics for students from 12 to 18 years old.

Programming Projects

Automated Residue Scale, Reforest Start Up (Santiago, August 2018 to date)

Automated scale to measure recycled residues from users of Reforest's recycling pick up service. The scale connects through a Raspberry Pi to a RESTful API written in nodejs. I lead the project and was in charge of the hardware part. The RESTApi was design and reviewed by me but programmed by a student of mine.

Education

Pontificia Universidad Católica de Chile, Master In Physics (Santiago, Chile, August 2017 to August 2019)

Pontificia Universidad Católica de Chile, B. Sc. Degree in Physics, (Santiago, Chile, March 2012 to July 2017)

Universidad de Chile, Summer School in Biotechnology, (Santiago, Chile, January 2008)

Colegio Pucalán Montessori (Santiago, Chile, 2010 Promotion)

Riccarton High School (New Zealand , October 2008 to march 2009)

Skills & Languages

Programming languages and digital tools

Advanced: Python, LaTeX

Intermediate: Arduino, Google Cloud Platform, HTML & CSS

Basic: JavaScript, NodeJS

Languages: Native Spanish, fluid English, and basic French.

References

PhD. Enrique Muñoz Tavera. Head of the Doctoral Program at the School of Physics, Universidad Católica de Chile. <u>munoztavera@gmail.com</u>

Paulina Vigneaux. Academic coordinator at Pucalán Montessori High School. pvigneaux@pucalan.cl